Hello everyone, in this tutorial video, we will learn how to make pockets in Marvelous Designer.
First, let's make a basic pocket.
Since we want to sew the pockets on the clothes, we need to use the inner rectangle on the clothes to drag the pattern of the pocket.
Click on it and drag it to make a rectangle.
Or you can use the inner rectangle tool to click on the left button to enter the exact number to create.
After creating, we can use the adjustment tool to drag the inner rectangle to adjust the position of the pocket.
Or we can shrink the pattern.
Next, in the right-click menu, we can select the rectangle as the pattern.
Then we put it in the 2D and 3D window.
After arranging them, we use the line sewing tool to click on the line on the panel and the pocket panel we have extracted.
Sew the three sides together.
The top edge is not sewn.
Then turn on the simulation.
The function of the sewing line will sew this pocket.
And because there is no sewing line at the top, it is now in the opening state.
So we have a simple pocket.
Next, let's take a look.
How to increase the thickness of this pocket.
First, you have to understand that when we increase the thickness of the pocket, only these three sewn edges will increase the thickness.
So here we are going to use the edge panel tool to select these three edges separately.
Then right-click to select the panel outline expansion to squeeze out the thickness of its side edge.
Note that our diameter and expansion number.
Here, our diameter is actually the width of its side edge.
If we want to expand the number, we can fill in 1 first.
Remember to select the inner line here.
So that we can continue to make other adjustments to the original rectangular edges.
Here, our side angle will be the default angle in the default situation.
In other words, they will be extended together.
Here we need to switch it to five corners.
So that the part we expand will not be linked together.
Then we press the control key to turn on the simulation.
Let's take a look at the simulation.
You can see that the thickness of the side edge is automatically applied.
Because our side panel has been expanded to its side panel outline.
Next, we are going to sew the two sides together.
Because now if we turn on the simulation and drag the panel, you will see that its side edge is not sewn together.
We use the edge panel tool to sew it up.
Then we can put these just used panel outline expansion.
The fold angle of the inner line automatically generated.
Adjust from default 180 to 0.
In this way, the position of these inner lines will default to the front of the panel.
So we will see that it is folded in a very round and angular way.
Then we choose to expand the panel outline and this inner line just now.
When selecting at the same time, right-click to select according to the line generation inner line.
So we can create a fold line in the middle of the two lines.
After we have created it, we first simulate it and apply it.
Then we are going to start preparing for the effect of folding pockets.
First of all, make sure that the display method in 3D space is the texture surface.
So that we can distinguish the shape of the panel.
Then we now need to fold the middle line inward.
So we want to set their folding angle to 360 degrees.
So if the folding angle applied to an inner line is greater than 180 degrees.
Then it is in this panel.
Fold inward.
In order to make the isolation effect of the panel more smooth.
We first reduce the particle diameter and then simulate it.
Now we turn the view.
You can see that this pocket already has the effect of folding.
Next, let's learn how to put the bottom of the pocket up.
First of all, we use the editor to delete the horizontal line.
Then we need to fold it up.
First of all, we need to remove the foldable position.
First of all, we choose the plus point line tool.
Right-click on these two original panel lines.
So we can enter the specific value.
Then here we want to enter the line length as 5 mm.
The length of this plus point is actually half of the panel line we just made.
After adding a point, we select the end point of the middle line.
Drag it to this point.
Then here we will see that in the process of dragging the inner line.
The bottom point did not change with it.
For example, here I have raised the inner line.
But there is no center point at the bottom.
So we have to select the three inner lines in the middle.
Right-click and select the increase point to the panel line.
There will be a breakpoint automatically on the panel line.
Then we can drag and select the frame in the 2D window.
At the same time select the breakpoint of the inner line.
And the point on the panel line.
Then drag it according to the pink straight line.
To the level corresponding to the straight line just now.
Now, according to the effect in the 3D window.
We will see that the side has been processed.
Then the position of our bottom is the same.
Do the same process.
Of course, on the other side.
You can directly drag the point we have created.
Then in the process of dragging the point.
Right-click on the mouse.
You can enter a specific value.
This is also possible.
All you have to remember is that the point you move.
Is the same as the width of half of what we just did.
In fact, we decide to use these values.
Just to make it more convenient.
To match the length of these lines.
Because now we have this triangular position.
The length of each side is certain.
Then you can use the line
To sew the two sides of the gap together.
Now we can see.
After opening the simulation.
The panel will automatically be put together.
Then we turn to the back.
Press Shift Q to hide the panel on the back.
Then press Shift A.
After hiding the virtual model.
We look closely at the inside of this pocket.
You will see.
Although the gaps are sewn together.
But they are not sewn in the middle.
So we need to fix them in the middle.
Here.
We need to use the line sewing tool.
Put it on both sides.
Like this.
Pay attention to the direction.
They are relative.
After sewing.
Press the control key to simulate.
If you don't know the direction.
You can use the blue point in the three bottom windows.
To match.
Now it's sewn up.
And it's a folded state.
That's why we did it before.
There are strict requirements for these lengths.
In fact, as long as they are left and right.
Can be sewn together.
It's the same.
Then we adjust the other side in the same way.
Remind again.
Don't forget to sew the left and right sides together.
Now.
Because we sewed up these gaps.
So now we look from the side.
You can see it here.
It's basically closed.
Next, let's learn.
How to fix this pocket tighter.
First of all.
In real life.
Many times.
The bottom of this square shape.
There will be an oblique line on the side of his pocket.
Is to sew up the pocket.
On the pants.
So here.
We also use the internal multidirectional line tool.
According to the two straight lines we created just now.
To draw an oblique inner line.
Then we use the line powder tool.
Sew them up left and right.
In this way.
The bottom is sewn up here.
Then we will start to draw on the clothes.
The line that will be used later.
Here.
We use the internal multidirectional line tool.
Press the Shift key.
You can create a line along the corner.
If you want to change the length of the line.
We can use the plus point division function.
The shortcut key is X.
Then on the inner line.
Right click.
Enter the same value as we just set.
That is 5 mm.
Then use the internal multidirectional line tool.
Draw an oblique line.
Then put these two.
Then sew these two inner lines together.
After sewing up.
The corner of the bottom of the pocket.
Will be sewed together with the body.
In order to fix it.
If we want to lengthen this inner line.
We can drag this point with the editor.
Then in the process of dragging the point.
Press the Ctrl key.
Can be extended along the original rhythm.
When dragging and pressing the Ctrl key.
To add.
Press the right mouse button.
You can enter the specific value.
Then we can go to the body.
To extend this inner line.
To extend the equal value.
Now the inner line.
It doesn't matter between the inner line and the inner line.
But don't forget.
Before we fixed the gap.
On this inner line.
So here.
We use the editor.
The line tool.
Drag the bottom of this line.
Move it to the blue point.
That is to say.
The equal position of the line.
We usually.
When you usually create the powder line.
You have to pay attention.
The length between the powder lines.
Is it right?
Then here.
We do the process of making the bag.
It's almost done.
Then everyone will say.
I used to use those inner lines.
The border.
Do it according to the inner line of the curve.
Can I draw this board directly?
It is also possible.
After we remove the board.
First of all.
We delete these two extra straight lines.
Then use the editor.
Then use the edit board tool.
Select these few lines.
Press the Shift key.
Is it possible to choose more?
Don't forget.
Then we choose.
When the panel line is expanded.
Choose two in the number.
So it will automatically.
The inner line.
That was to show you before.
So I didn't use this step directly.
If you expand the panel line directly twice.
We don't need to use.
These functions are aligned to the panel line.
Just remember.
When making a gap.
Try to let.
Every edge is correct.
Then we can use the edit board.
Function.
Select these few internal lines.
Then apply it to him.
A straight angle.
Smaller than 180 degrees.
The inner line in the middle.
It's over 180 degrees.
The final.